<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on thalesbruno</title>
    <link>https://thalesbr.uno/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on thalesbruno</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 17:07:28 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thalesbr.uno/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Variables</title>
      <link>https://thalesbr.uno/posts/numerical-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 17:07:28 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thalesbr.uno/posts/numerical-variables/</guid>
      <description>Numerical variables, also known as quantitative variables, are the type of data that represent something measurable or countable like frequency, measurement, etc. Another attribute of numerical variables is that they are always numbers that can be placed in a meaningful order with consistent intervals.
As examples of quantitative variables we may mention:
 Weight Height Sales Production units Movie Ratings  Discrete and continuous Numerical variables may be either discrete or continuous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Categorical Variables</title>
      <link>https://thalesbr.uno/posts/categorical-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 17:10:09 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thalesbr.uno/posts/categorical-variables/</guid>
      <description>A categorical variable (sometimes called a nominal variable) is a variable that can assume one of a limited number of possible values described as categories and there is no intrinsic ordering to the categories. It uses labels, names, or other descriptors (even numbers) to identify exclusive categories or types of things.
As an example of a categorical variable we may mention Nationality having values like Brazilian, Canadian, French, etc., and we can see that there is no ordering between the values: we cannot say that Brazilian is higher than Canadian.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>